THIS PROGRAM CONTAINS AI-GENERATED CONTENT
[♪ dramatic music playing]
[screams]
CASE 2:
GWANDONG BYEOLGOK: THE EXILE MURDER CASE
[♪ theme song playing]
MURDER CLUB: LIAR'S TABLE
[person 1 exclaims]
FIRST PLAYER ENTERS
What's all this?
EOM JIYOON
COMEDIAN
So this is what it looks like.
FASCINATING
[exclaims]
We're playing a board game like this?
When it comes to board games, I'm really…
[person 2] Hello.
It's our second time meeting, right?
- We met once before.
- Yes.
- How have you been?
- The same old.
PANI BOTTLE
YOUTUBER
You're a pro at survival games.
- Me?
- Yes.
Are you mistaking me for someone else?
I'm the worst at survival games.
I'm known for being totally useless.
- I thought I was early, but I'm third.
- [Pani Bottle] Hello.
- [Jiyoon] Hello.
- Hey there.
- I enjoy your work.
- [Jiyoon] Thank you.
You've done this before, right?
We both did it together.
It was so funny. I laughed so much.
He slapped the culprit
in the back of the head at one point.
- [Yangrak] Be careful.
- For being guilty?
You were there at 2:17 a.m.,
looking right at the camera.
- Wait a minute.
- I've got chills.
- You little!
- [others chuckling]
Why did you hit me?
[Kim Doyun] He got physical!
- I was sure it was him.
- [Pani Bottle chuckles]
HIS HUNCH WAS ACCURATE
We all cracked up.
- Hello.
- [Jiyoon] Hello.
- All in a good mood.
- Hello.
- [Yangrak] My gosh.
- You're as tall as a basketball player.
- Nice to see you.
[Jiyoon]
He's got an unfair advantage as an actor.
I'm the only one who's never acted here.
[inhales deeply]
This is bad. I'm a terrible actor.
Aren't you acting now?
- You're acting as we speak.
- [chuckles] Playing pretend.
- You're acting now.
- Me?
I'm really not.
- [person 5] Hello.
- [Jiyoon] Hello. Oh, my gosh!
- [Pani Bottle] You're a chef, right?
- [Jiyoon] Mr. Iron Arms.
Yes, I was on Culinary Class Wars.
My nickname was Iron Arms.
Forget everything else,
when this is over, can we get a table?
- Yes, can we get an invite?
- [Yangrak chuckles]
- Of course.
- [Jiyoon] Seriously.
Can we go today after filming?
- Sure.
- [others chuckle]
TALKED INTO A TEAM DINNER
- [radio static]
- What's happening?
STARTLED
[host]
Welcome to Murder Club: Liar's Table.
This is a special space
where you'll play a game
called "Murder Mystery."
In today's Murder Mystery,
you will try to identify
the culprit hidden among you.
You will each be assigned a unique role
and play the game as that character.
There is only one culprit,
but every player has their own secret.
To win this game,
you are allowed to lie, conceal the truth,
and act deceptively.
The game consists of five rounds.
At the start of each round,
one clue will be revealed
to the entire group,
and all the players will pick out
one card clue and one object clue.
The card clues are confidential
and can only be shared
during private conversations.
The object clues
can be examined by all players.
After collecting the clues,
you will have a 15-minute discussion.
Starting Round 2, you will have time
for private conversations.
After the group discussion,
you will have five minutes
to talk secretly
in the private conversation zones.
In Round 5, the final round,
you will make your final vote.
After the final group discussion,
you will vote for the person
you suspect to be the culprit.
Now, you will be assigned your roles.
Please choose one of the files
in front of you.
This seems to be
the only female character.
- Yun Suyeon?
- Yes.
- I'll pick my favorite color, orange.
- [Yangrak] Gosh.
[Juseong] I feel like I should be Musoe.
[Jiyoon] Since it means "iron."
A character named Bokgil?
Since it's set in the Joseon era…
Isn't Bokgil a dog's name?
- [Jiyoon] Maybe it's a Jindo.
- "Come here, Bokgil!"
THE CULPRIT HAS BEEN CHOSEN
I'm Yun Igyeong.
[Yangrak] Is Yun Igyeong
- some kind of nobleman?
- I am, yes.
- "An exiled official."
- A public official.
I'm high-ranking, but I've been exiled.
[♪ dramatic music playing]
YUN IGYEONG
AGE 40, FORMER LOCAL OFFICIAL,
IN EXILE
And Yun Suyeon is my daughter.
- [Yangrak] Daughter?
- So I am.
YUN SUYEON
AGE 21, YUN IGYEONG'S DAUGHTER
[Pani Bottle] Bokgil is a slave.
- I'm a slave?
- [Jiyoon] Yes.
[others laugh]
BOKGIL
AGE 25, YUN IGYEONG'S SLAVE
[Pani Bottle] Musoe is a maid.
- [gasps] Oh, Musoe's a woman!
- [Sungrok] It's a female character.
- [Yangrak] She's a maid.
- It's a woman.
[Jiyoon] She's Suyeon's maid.
MUSOE
AGE 21, YUN SUYEON'S MAID
[Jiyoon] The Traveler is an outsider.
[Pani Bottle] His identity's unknown.
"A rare air of nobility
in this mountain village."
THE TRAVELER
AGE 43, MYSTERIOUS IDENTITY
FATHER AND DAUGHTER
SLAVE, MAID
TRAVELER
[host] The second story
of Murder Club will now begin.
"Gwandong Byeolgok:
The Exile Murder Case."
Gwandong Byeolgok?
[narrator] Despite the spread of famine
across the eight provinces of Joseon,
the king demanded a raise in taxes.
Yun Igyeong, a local official,
saw the people's suffering
and submitted a petition
opposing the tax reform.
His petition angered the king
and Yun Igyeong ended up in exile.
With his only daughter, Yun Suyeon,
and her maid, Musoe,
he began a life in exile
with the help of Bokgil,
a slave he met there.
Then one day,
a traveler he'd never met before
asked to stay the night.
Late in the night,
as the five people got ready for bed,
the incident took place.
The next morning,
Musoe went into the back yard
and found an unidentified dead body
with a disfigured face.
[host] Here is the first shared clue.
[Bokgil] Oh, goodness.
- Their face is completely disfigured.
- [Suyeon gasps]
It looks like it was torn by a wild beast.
- Is it a man or a woman?
- [Bokgil groans]
They're too disfigured to tell.
[The Traveler] I think it's a man.
They're wearing pants.
[host] Pick the card clues for Round 1.
Every player has
a total of five card clues.
Each card contains a secret
that no other player knows.
In every round except for the fifth round,
the players can take one card
from the person they suspect.
Use the collected clues
to determine who the culprit is.
- We can pick any, right?
- That's right.
I'll take one of my dad's.
I'll go for this one.
Okay, then. Me too.
[Suyeon] You've lost two cards.
The Traveler is obviously
the most suspicious.
I'll take one from here.
- [Bokgil] Musoe's card.
- One of Musoe's cards.
You're a bit far,
but I've been doubting you, lady.
[Suyeon] How could you doubt me
after all these years?
THE PLAYERS CAN SHARE
WHAT THEY KNOW FROM THE CARD CLUES
BUT THEY CAN ONLY SHOW THE ACTUAL CARD
DURING PRIVATE CONVERSATIONS
-It's time to collect the object clues.
- [Suyeon] Okay. Let's go.
[Igyeong] Let's see what we have.
EVIDENCE ZONE
EACH PLAYER MAY COLLECT
1 OBJECT CLUE PER ROUND
THE OWNER OF THE CLUE IS UNSPECIFIED
- I'm taking this one.
- [Bokgil] Which one?
[host] Round 1 will now begin.
Are we now in the Joseon era?
Shall we talk like people in the old days?
ANXIOUS ABOUT BEING
LAST IN THE PECKING ORDER
Hey, Bokgil!
- Bokgil!
- Why, you little…
What?
- "You little"?
- Wait. You were a lord?
- How dare you, you lowly slave?
- [Igyeong] The nerve…
My ears must be deceiving me.
Why, of course.
BACKING DOWN
Bokgil looks a lot older than his age.
- He's worked too hard.
- [Igyeong] He's had a tough life.
What is that in your hand, Suyeon?
Father, this is
a bloodstained handkerchief.
ROUND 1 OBJECT CLUE:
BLOODSTAINED HANDKERCHIEF
Seeing how elegant the embroidery is,
I think it likely
belongs to someone noble.
People like me and Bokgil
could not use such a handkerchief.
Bokgil has always had
rather sticky fingers.
It's a baseless accusation.
You're saying Bokgil stole it?
What kind of slave
wears a watch like this?
- [Igyeong] Wait a minute.
- No, no.
- What is this, Bokgil?
- [Suyeon] You stole it, didn't you?
[Bokgil] Let's see. Object number 14.
WHAT OBJECT CLUE DID BOKGIL BRING?
ROUND 1 OBJECT CLUE: RASPBERRIES
- [Igyeong] Raspberries?
- [Bokgil] Yes, raspberries.
Try one, Bokgil.
You go first.
What did you say?
- [others chuckle]
- How dare you!
[stammers] Oh, right. Noble lady.
- I forgot.
- Why, this little…
This is all a bit…
STRUGGLING TO ADJUST
It's outright insubordination!
[Igyeong] You shouldn't eat that.
It's definitely a raspberry.
[Bokgil] But what can raspberries prove?
I found a silver dagger.
[Bokgil] A silver dagger?
There's blood on it.
Don't women carry them around
- to protect themselves?
- Ladies usually
carry it for self-defense.
Why would you do such a thing, my lady?
But Musoe just now…
She shouldn't have ever
laid hands on one before,
but she suspiciously
whipped it out like a seasoned pro.
It has iron in it, doesn't it?
WHOSE SILVER DAGGER IS IT?
Let's look at what I brought.
ROUND 1 OBJECT CLUE: SILK CLOTHES
[all gasp]
- Silk clothing.
- [Bokgil] It's conclusive proof.
It's some fancy hanbok.
[Suyeon] It's a rich man's clothes.
It looks like the Traveler's size.
[The Traveler] A passing traveler couldn't
wear such fancy clothes.
But who are you, by the way?
I'm just passing through.
A wandering traveler.
Usually, travelers
- have dirty faces…
- That's right.
…and tattered clothes.
- But he's too dashing.
- His looks aren't of an ordinary traveler.
- What's your object clue?
- [Bokgil] Your clothes aren't…
- What's that?
- [The Traveler] It's an herbal tonic.
"Arsenic, chive seeds, wolfsbane…"
[Bokgil] Oh, that means…
- [Suyeon] Is it poison?
-…it's a poison.
Give it a taste, Bokgil.
WHY DO YOU KEEP TELLING ME TO TASTE…
- She's treating you like a mutt, Bokgil.
- [others laugh]
[Bokgil] That's poison. Don't eat that!
- Come on, Bokgil.
- No, thank you.
How could a lowly man like me drink that?
But if they fed the victim poison,
the poison would have killed them.
So why did they disfigure their face?
It seems like the victim
was slashed by a blade,
and more notably,
they have a blue bruise
on the back of their hand.
Maybe they tried to shield themselves.
- They were struck.
- It's a possibility.
[Igyeong] That long slash across the chest
looks like a blade wound.
You can't do that with a silver dagger.
- [Bokgil] Of course, not.
- It would only leave a small cut.
It had to be a long blade
handled by someone skilled in combat.
His face is mangled.
And it seems like he was
dragged across the ground.
Maybe he had a really handsome face,
so he was targeted by someone
who had reason to envy him.
- Why did she look at us two?
- [others chuckle]
I didn't mean anything by it, Father.
Why look at us two, of all people?
[Igyeong] The cards we picked earlier…
- [Suyeon] You mean this?
- [Bokgil] The ones we picked.
Whose was it?
I took it from my father.
- It's Yun Igyeong's card.
- You suspect your father.
There was a note in his pillow.
It said, "Don't make any moves,"
in the sense of keeping a low profile.
It seems political.
INFO FROM THE KING'S COURT?
Was something going on?
Something political?
- I can't tell you.
- [Bokgil] It's because of politics
that he was exiled.
Politically speaking,
whether he was framed or actually guilty,
he's considered a criminal.
You're very smart, Bokgil.
[Suyeon] Why would someone send
this note to a criminal?
SNEAKING A PEEK
- How dare you sneak a peek!
- [others chuckle]
So this is the kind of sly trick
- you have up your sleeve.
- No.
You're the only one here
wearing magnifying glasses.
I also obtained a clue.
- Go on, Dad.
- I took a card
- from the passing traveler
- [The Traveler] "Dad."
and it was a list of books.
- A list of books.
- Okay.
Was it The Analects?
I'm not good with Chinese characters.
[Bokgil] The Analects? That means…
[Igyeong] It's a bit advanced
for an ordinary traveler.
- He's a learned traveler.
- Yeah, if he's reading The Analects.
He's reading Confucian Classics.
Not a lot of people can read,
I can't even spell my name.
And it's just two words, "Bok Gili."
Your name is "Bok Gili"?
- Not just Bokgil?
- [Igyeong] Is Bok a surname?
- Your name's just "Gil"?
- Which Bok clan is it?
I don't even know that much.
But why did you have
The Analects in your bag?
[The Traveler]
You can learn that much anywhere.
I picked a witness testimony.
The Traveler,
judging by his appearance,
doesn't seem like a commoner
but a very high-ranking person.
What are you doing in this village?
- Why my house, of all places?
- [Bokgil] Where were you headed?
It is very suspicious.
[Suyeon] Who told him we had room?
- [Bokgil] He's the most suspicious.
- [Suyeon] It wasn't me.
[Bokgil] Where were you headed?
He wasn't with us before.
He appeared out of the blue
on the very day of the murder.
Within 24 hours.
I feel like he is the most likely suspect.
[host] Round 1 is over.
We didn't get to discuss everything.
Musoe didn't even get a chance to talk.
Come on, man!
ROUND 1 CARD CLUES
PILLOW NOTE, TRAVELER'S BAG,
VILLAGE ELDER'S WITNESS STATEMENT
[host] Here is a new shared clue.
BLUEPRINT OF THE EXILE GROUNDS
Hang on!
There's a trail of blood.
A TRAIL OF BLOOD
SHOWING THE KILLER'S ROUTE
- This was…
- I see.
The guest room, kitchen,
Yun Igyeong's room, and the main hall.
That's the route.
This shows Musoe and I are innocent.
Same for me.
- Yeah, Bokgil too.
- That means…
Thank you, my lady.
FULLY IMMERSED IN HIS ROLE
This narrows it down
to the Traveler and Yun Igyeong.
[Suyeon] The route is a little odd.
[Bokgil] Just based on this.
[host] Pick the card clues for Round 2.
[Bokgil] Give me one.
BOKGIL TAKES A CARD FROM MUSOE
What's my daughter been up to?
We haven't talked much
since you hit puberty.
YUN IGYEONG TAKES A CARD FROM YUN SUYEON
- Now you're suspecting me?
- [The Traveler sighs]
I find you suspicious, sir.
MUSOE TAKES A CARD FROM YUN IGYEONG
I find you suspicious, Mr. Traveler.
YUN SUYEON TAKES A CARD FROM THE TRAVELER
[host] Head over to the evidence zone
and collect object clues.
I'll just take this bundle.
What's this?
[Igyeong] You go first, Musoe.
ROUND 2
[Musoe] It's someone's belongings.
- [Suyeon] Belongings?
- [Musoe] And shoes.
[Igyeong] Whose is it?
[Suyeon] Wait a minute.
Bokgil, you scoundrel!
That's your personal color, isn't it?
What are my clothes doing in there?
- Wait. What's that?
- [all exclaim]
- [Bokgil] What's that?
- [Suyeon] What is it?
- [Suyeon] A hairpin?
- That's so random.
[Igyeong] But these are men's clothes.
WHAT DOES THE NOTE SAY?
[The Traveler] Well?
[Musoe] "Forgive my boldness,
but can I spend
the rest of my life by your side?"
That's what it says.
IT SEEMS LIKE A MARRIAGE PROPOSAL
- Isn't it a love letter?
- [Musoe] Yeah.
[The Traveler] Bokgil was
in love with you, my lady.
- [Bokgil] No. It was Musoe.
- [The Traveler] Was it mutual?
COULD IT BE?
I think Bokgil
stole my hairpin
and planned to run away with Musoe.
BLUSH
[Igyeong] Lovers fleeing at night?
But who wrote that note?
- It must have been you.
- Me?
But I can't even spell own my name.
- [Bokgil] Come on.
- Let's examine my object clue.
A hair comb?
- [Suyeon] It's a fine-tooth comb.
- Yeah.
[Igyeong] It's women's clothing.
A WOMAN'S BELONGINGS
A ring? There are two!
- [Suyeon] The hairpin earlier--
- Wedding rings?
[Musoe] Don't they seem like Suyeon's?
It looks like
when two people pack their belongings
to run away together.
A MAN'S BELONGINGS
WITH A PROPOSAL FOR MARRIAGE
AND A WOMAN'S BELONGINGS
WITH WEDDING RINGS
But since they're jade rings,
I think they belong to the lady.
They're yours, my lady.
[Musoe] I couldn't own a jade ring.
You two stole them from me.
HOW MANY THIEVES ARE IN THIS HOUSEHOLD?
We're not catching thieves,
we're looking for the murderer.
They were actually my belongings.
I packed them.
I'll be in big trouble if they found out
about my relations with Bokgil.
I don't want anyone to know about it.
WERE THEY LOVERS?
Why did you two steal all my stuff?
SIGH
Something's always missing
whenever I get back home.
- Where did you get that ring?
- [others chuckle]
- It's mine, isn't it?
- [Bokgil] No, my lady.
Ms. Paeng gave it to me.
"Ms. Paeng."
Wait. Who is Ms. Paeng?
- Who's Ms. Paeng?
- [Igyeong] Who is that?
Bring out the sword.
This is key evidence. Look here.
Is there blood on it?
Right, this sword here…
- [Bokgil] Be careful.
-…is huge.
- [Bokgil] Gosh.
- [The Traveler] Wow.
But as for any bloodstains…
- [Bokgil] Are there any?
- It looks clean.
They must have wiped it.
They tried for a perfect murder.
- [gasps]
- The murder weapon, the silver dagger…
What is it?
Earlier, my handkerchief
was soaked with blood, right?
They must have used it to wipe this sword.
HANDKERCHIEF USED TO WIPE THE BLOOD?
- Father!
- [Bokgil chuckles]
Why is that mine?
It's either yours or the Traveler's.
If you put the sword
and the handkerchief together,
"wealthy" and "male"
are the words that come to mind.
Two people fit that description.
I don't want to believe it,
but one is my father.
The other is the Traveler.
WHOSE HANDKERCHIEF AND SWORD IS IT?
Before we solve this,
the card I picked said
that Bokgil
brewed tonics.
TRACES OF SECRETLY BREWED TONICS
There were traces.
Tonic?
DID BOKGIL BREW TONICS
ON THE LOCAL MOUNTAIN?
You are the absolute worst, Bokgil.
I am innocent, my lady.
- You're up to all sorts.
- No, listen.
Every morning and night…
- The type of tonic is what matters.
- [Bokgil] Exactly.
But that tonic before
was a poison, as we saw earlier.
[Bokgil]
I don't know anything about poisons.
Where would I get that?
- Where do they sell poison?
- [Igyeong] He's dangerous.
- He's a dangerous man.
- [Bokgil] Gosh.
Bokgil keeps insisting it wasn't him.
I don't know exactly
who he secretly brewed the tonic for,
but I think he's hiding something.
I'm sorry to interrupt,
but this is really important.
The blue mark on the wrist
of the dead victim isn't a bruise.
They were born with that mark.
- It's a birth mark?
- [Igyeong] Yeah.
- It's a kind of mole?
- I mention this because
on my daughter's bookshelf,
there's a Birth Chamber Log that mentions
a newborn baby with a mark
on the back of their right hand.
A BABY BORN WITH A BLUE MARK
ON THE BACK OF ITS HAND?
But why was that record
in my daughter's room?
Does that mean Lady Suyeon had a child?
What nonsense!
She's an unmarried woman.
How could you suggest that?
- Out of the blue.
- What an accusation.
Wait. I didn't get to share
my card clue in Round 1, right?
NERVOUS
But Lady Suyeon wrote,
"I didn't menstruate."
What? Oh.
So she was pregnant?
- Unbelievable.
- The record I found was about births.
It was a delivery log.
So it could be her child.
But Suyeon's still…
The victim's too old to be her child.
- We look about the same age.
- [Igyeong] Can you imagine?
- [The Traveler] How old are you?
- The victim looks older.
Reveal your age!
I'm just 21 years old, you bastards!
- Did I have a child when I was two?
- Then this guy…
She'd have to give birth
before she was even born.
- He looks older than me.
- She gave birth in the womb.
Another possibility is
that the victim's son
had the same birthmark,
or something like that.
It's another possibility.
The Birth Chamber Log is pretty major.
How did that come out as evidence?
WHAT SECRET IS SUYEON HIDING?
[host] Starting Round 2,
the private conversation zones are open.
Anyone who wants a private conversation
can freely access this zone.
I never doubted you, my lord.
The person I suspect is none other
than Suyeon.
- Because right now--
- Your own daughter?
She has too many secrets.
- The birth record we discussed earlier
- Yes.
and the blue mark
on the victim's right hand…
There's a lot I don't know
about my own daughter.
She has a lot of secrets.
You seem to have some connection
to the dead victim.
I don't know them at all.
- The birth record.
- Yeah.
It seems like you have a secret.
I've never seen it before.
I have no idea why it was in my room.
You are obviously hiding something.
But both the cards I picked
mention a dark rumor circulating at court
and warned you to be on your guard.
- Mmm.
- So here's what I suspect.
The victim tried to get you,
so you eliminated him first.
WAS THE TRAVELER IN DANGER?
I'm only telling you two
since we're having a private conversation.
The truth is,
the reason for my lavish attire
is because I'm Grand Prince Hwiryeong.
- Grand Prince Hwiryeong?
- I'm the king's younger brother.
- [Musoe gasps]
[announcer]
Here comes the Grand Prince Hwiryeong!
GRAND PRINCE HWIRYEONG
KING'S YOUNGER BROTHER,
PLANS TO USURP THE THRONE
If I keep hiding my identity,
they could mistake me for the killer.
So I had no choice
but to reveal some of the truth.
THE TRAVELER'S IDENTITY
IS FINALLY REVEALED
Gosh. High Prince.
Grand Prince.
- Right, Grand Prince. [chuckles]
- Grand Prince.
Do you understand now?
Please have mercy.
But why did you kill someone,
Your Highness?
I did not kill them.
I heard that Yun Igyeong
had fallen on hard times.
So I disguised myself as a traveler--
- You came to help?
- I came to help.
But why hide your identity?
If I didn't adopt this disguise,
- I could become a target of assassins.
- Mmm.
So I had to keep my identity a secret.
- Like secret royal inspectors.
- Exactly.
He said he was the Grand Prince Hwiryeong,
so I'm convinced something went down
between him and Lord Yun.
Since he's been exiled,
he might be planning
a revolt with the grand prince.
Or their close relationship
might be the reason
he was exiled in the first place.
ARE THEY ALLIES?
[host]
Here is the shared clue for Round 3.
It's an audio of the murder incident.
DOOR OPENING
- [door closes]
- [footsteps approaching]
SHATTERING
[sword unsheathes]
A SLASHING SWORD
[sword swishes]
LIMPING
- [footsteps]
- [door opens and closes]
SLASHING SWORD 2
- [liquid spills]
- [victim breathing heavily]
[thuds]
[door opens]
DRAGGING
Is that the corpse being dragged?
[footsteps running]
FLEEING
[door closes]
That's brutal.
There were two sword sounds, right?
But there was no scream
when the sword was first swung.
There was a scream the second time.
A swing and a miss.
- First it felt like practice.
- Like it was forced.
But only one person died, right?
- Not two?
- [Bokgil] Just one person.
[host] Pick out the card clues.
TIME TO SELECT CARD CLUES
THE TRAVELER TAKES ONE FROM MUSOE
MUSOE TAKES ONE FROM YUN IGYEONG
YUN SUYEON TAKES ONE FROM BOKGIL
YUN IGYEONG TAKES ONE FROM YUN SUYEON
BOKGIL TAKES ONE FROM MUSOE
[Suyeon sighs]
The object clues are low-key important.
All right. Let's take this one.
[host] Round 3 will now begin.
Did this heart symbol exist
in the Joseon era?
ROUND 3 OBJECT CLUE: A LOVE NOTE
MY LOVE, BOKGIL
[Suyeon] "My love, Bokgil."
MUSOE
"Musoe"?
What the heck?
WHAT'S THE STORY BEHIND THIS?
I think it's true that Musoe liked me.
IS SUYEON JEALOUS?
To be honest, since Bokgil first moved in,
- I couldn't take my eyes off him.
- How mortifying.
MUSOE BRAVELY CONFESSES HER FEELINGS
[♪ romantic music playing]
[heartbeat thumping]
LOVE TRIANGLE
YUN SUYEON, BOKGIL, MUSOE
How mortifying.
Flirting under someone else's roof.
Musoe, you little…
What were you doing yesterday night?
- [Bokgil] Yeah, what were you doing?
- Last night?
I actually heard
Bokgil and Lady Yun
planned to run away together.
What are you on about?
I was asleep in my room.
That's not true, my lady.
- [others laugh]
- I think we've been caught.
What are you talking about?
Why deny it now?
I noticed he looked at you
in an unusual way.
He just has weird eyes.
- Your taste is men is even weirder.
- [others laugh]
- [Musoe] So…
- Oh man, Bokgil.
I have never in my life
dated a guy with sideburns.
- - You were saying?
- So
after hearing you'd flee in the night,
I couldn't sleep.
so I went into the kitchen
to pack you some extra food,
like raspberries.
-That's what those raspberries were for.
- [Bokgil] Ah.
Oh, I see.
I think that could be a lie
because Musoe loves Bokgil,
so why would she pack raspberries
for you to flee together?
- It makes no sense.
- [Igyeong] It's odd.
I think it's a mix of lie and truth.
Did you plan to flee in the night?
No, Dad.
- It is true, sir.
- [others laugh]
Who's telling the truth?
[Igyeong]
Are you ashamed of your boyfriend?
What were you doing yesterday night?
I'll explain what happened.
- Tell the truth.
- Explain.
To be honest,
Bokgil was just a one-night stand.
A one-night stand? What's that?
I don't really love him, I just--
You said you did!
It was just pillow talk.
You said I was just your type!
- I was just talking about your body.
- [others laugh]
HOT BODY
It's because you're so strong.
- That's part of his charm.
- [Suyeon] Exactly.
I didn't tell you because I was
afraid you'd get angry.
And I was a bit embarrassed.
I thought Bokgil would be good-looking,
but he's really not.
BOKGIL AND SUYEON REALLY WERE LOVERS
When a man and woman date for a long time…
TAKEN ABACK
Sooner or later,
- you cross a line you shouldn't.
- You crossed it.
A relationship like ours
is forbidden in these times.
- That's why you planned to run away.
- Yes, far away.
We planned to run away tonight,
but because of this murder case,
here we are.
But
in Musoe's kitchen ceiling,
she kept a book saying pregnant women
should avoid cooling foods like buckwheat
and an excess of stimulating herbs
like cinnamon twigs and ginger.
It's a book called
Compendium of Secret Remedies.
Things like buckwheat
are bad for pregnant women.
- She put them in her food intentionally?
- [Hwiryeong] It's possible.
Musoe was in love with Bokgil,
but he got Suyeon pregnant,
so out of jealousy,
she tried to induce a miscarriage
- and fed her buckwheat.
- You rotten brat!
- [Hwiryeong] That's it.
- That's so chilling.
It's true that I was jealous.
I was jealous,
so when she didn't get her period,
I did that out of jealousy.
- [Bokgil] It was Musoe's doing.
- [gasps] You tried to kill me?
Not you, just your baby.
- That's even worse! It's even more cruel.
- [others laugh]
MUSOE PLANNED REVENGE
BY COOKING WITH BUCKWHEAT
[Hwiryeong]
What were you doing last night, Lord Yun?
I got up at the Hour of the Ox.
- Around 1 o'clock?
- Yes.
Between the Traveler's room
and my bedroom
is where the victim lay dead.
If I left him there,
I knew I'd be the prime suspect.
Did you hear that sound at the end?
- That dragging sound?
- Yes.
I was the one who dragged him
and moved him over there.
AFTER FINDING THE BODY,
HE DRAGGED IT TO THE COURTYARD
That's why there's a trail here.
But I didn't kill him.
Well, that's a bit suspicious.
You could have just woken us up by saying,
- "There's a dead body here!"
- Yeah.
- Instead, you dragged the body…
- [Suyeon] Himself.
[sighs] I find that a bit…
It's because I'm in exile,
and something like this
could lead to greater trouble.
I can't risk arousing suspicion,
so that's why I moved the body.
The victim bled out
in front of my dad's room,
and the way he handled the body…
I find that the most suspicious.
I think my father has
some kind of political secret.
I think him and the Traveler
may have been in on it together.
Like they could be accomplices.
What were thee doing
at the time, Mr. Traveler?
- "Thee"?
- "Thee."
[Suyeon] Old language is hard.
[host] Round 3 is over.
What?
[host] A new zone will open in Round 4.
Please move to the back.
What's this?
[♪ traditional music playing]
[exclaims]
THE SHAMAN ZONE
- [Suyeon gasps]
- [Igyeong] It's a shaman.
Hello.
What is this place?
What is this zone for?
Did you bring the number cards?
Number cards? These?
SCROLL CLUE
OPEN A SCROLL THAT MATCHES THE NUMBER
OF THE RANDOM BONUS CARD
THAT CAME WITH THE OBJECT CLUE
I'll go first. Unlucky number four.
[♪ ominous music playing]
Number four.
- [Bokgil] What's that?
- [Suyeon gasps]
[Bokgil] Read it aloud.
[Suyeon] "Warning."
"Lowborn children are dying
due to the terrible famine."
"The evil practice of replacing
noble babies with lowborn babies
is all too common."
"Guard your children well
and prepare for the worst."
Someone's switching them.
Kids are being switched?
[Hwiryeong] All right, then.
Here's my number.
Number two.
- Oh, my. What is that?
- [Bokgil] Gosh.
[Suyeon] What does it say?
[Igyeong]
"I've lived someone else's life."
- Someone else's life?
- "I had to grow up
as a lowly servant."
"He is the cause
of all my suffering."
"I shall pay him back with your blood."
That's so scary. What does it mean?
It's written in blood.
[Igyeong] They were switched as a child,
so their life was upturned.
A CHANGE IN STATUS?
They were born into a noble family,
but they grew up poor.
BIRTH CHAMBER LOG
This is
about me?
Translated by Hannah Og Nam